export const JEWELLERYA2022 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Leather obtained from the elephant for making jewellery is referred to as",
A: "chamois.",
B: "hide.",
C: "on skin.",
D: "suede.",
answer: "B. Hide",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Acid solution used for etching is generally known as",
A: "adhesives.",
B: "fluxes.",
C: "mordants.",
D: "solvents.",
answer: "C. Mordants",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Select the metal which is produced from bauxite.",
A: "Aluminium",
B: "Copper",
C: "Silver",
D: "Tin",
answer: "A. Aluminium",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the listed metals is resistant to corrosion?",
A: "Copper",
B: "Brass",
C: "Iron",
D: "Silver",
answer: "D. Silver",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Identify the appropriate state of borax when soldering.",
A: "Cake",
B: "Granulated",
C: "Paste",
D: "Powder",
answer: "C. Paste",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following strokes of the saw frame blade does the cutting?",
A: "Diagonal",
B: "Downward",
C: "Sideways",
D: "Upwards",
answer: "B. Downward",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Annealing is best accomplished by using",
A: "hatchet.",
B: "blowtorch.",
C: "burners.",
D: "bellows.",
answer: "B. Blowtorch",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The jeweller’s scrap book is mainly used for",
A: "advertisement.",
B: "decoration.",
C: "reference.",
D: "sketching.",
answer: "C. Reference",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The design on a medallion showing balance is said to be",
A: "asymmetric.",
B: "equidistance.",
C: "equilibrium.",
D: "symmetric.",
answer: "D. Symmetric",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. One major economic importance of jewellery is for",
A: "decoration of kings.",
B: "muslim worship.",
C: "personal decoration.",
D: "storage of wealth.",
answer: "D. Storage of wealth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Worked on metals are pickled so as to",
A: "clear fire scales.",
B: "harden it.",
C: "lengthen it.",
D: "soften the metal.",
answer: "A. Clear fire scales",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following tools is used for reducing the thickness of a bezel?",
A: "Drawplate",
B: "Pliers",
C: "Pumice",
D: "Carborundum",
answer: "D. Carborundum",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Fusing two or more metals together is referred to as",
A: "alloying.",
B: "annealing.",
C: "electroplating.",
D: "ionizing.",
answer: "A. Alloying",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of these reactions can cause an explosion when a jeweller is at work?",
A: "Acid added to water",
B: "Dilute acid added to concentrated acid",
C: "Hot water added to cold dilute acid",
D: "Water added to acid",
answer: "D. Water added to acid",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The most appropriate tool for cutting clay slabs is",
A: "knife.",
B: "hacksaw.",
C: "spatula.",
D: "wire.",
answer: "D. Wire",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A kiln that is about to be used for enameling should first be",
A: "glazed.",
B: "cooled.",
C: "heated.",
D: "polished.",
answer: "C. Heated",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Paillons are materials used for",
A: "annealing.",
B: "etching.",
C: "cnameling.",
D: "soldering.",
answer: "D. Soldering",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. One main advantage of organizing a jewellery exhibition is the",
A: "addition of value to the items.",
B: "promotion of the products.",
C: "enhancement of the artist creativity.",
D: "socialization of art collectors.",
answer: "B. Promotion of the products",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The appropriate tool used in denting metal plates is",
A: "centre punch.",
B: "file.",
C: "jeweller’s saw.",
D: "nail.",
answer: "A. Centre punch",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Select the ferrous metal from the options.",
A: "Aluminium",
B: "Copper",
C: "Iron",
D: "Lead",
answer: "C. Iron",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Identify the softest metal from the options.",
A: "Aluminium",
B: "Bronze",
C: "Gold",
D: "Platinum",
answer: "C. Gold",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A perfect transverse cut of a bamboo for making bead is obtained by using",
A: "hacksaw.",
B: "jeweller’s saw.",
C: "pocket knife.",
D: "cutter,",
answer: "B. Jeweller’s saw",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Successful soldering is done by.",
A: "pickling.",
B: "bonding.",
C: "heating.",
D: "riveting.",
answer: "C. Heating",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. To obtain a finger ring ina circular shape, it must be shaped ona",
A: "hammer.",
B: "tongs.",
C: "mandrel.",
D: "tweezers",
answer: "C. Mandrel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Lacquer and polish are used on leather jewellery as",
A: "dyes.",
B: "finishes.",
C: "coatings.",
D: "preservatives.",
answer: "B. Finishes",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In etching, plastic containers are most appropriate for the solution because they",
A: "promote highly finished edges.",
B: "minimize formation of vapour.",
C: "increase corrosive action.",
D: "resist corrosive action.",
answer: "D. Resist corrosive action",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Waist beads are best strung on",
A: "cotton cord.",
B: "leather tong.",
C: "flexible wire.",
D: "elastic thread.",
answer: "D. Elastic thread",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A well finished jewellery item",
A: "maintains durability.",
B: "has protective abilities.",
C: "attracts high prices.",
D: "is worn by wealthy people.",
answer: "A. Maintains durability",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following pairs is decorative technique in bone jewellery?",
A: "Cutting and stippling",
B: "Filling and embossing",
C: "Scorching and incising",
D: "Chasing and stippling",
answer: "C. Scorching and incising",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Saw cuts and burrs from the edges of a metal are best removed by",
A: "buffing.",
B: "sanding.",
C: "filling.",
D: "planishing.",
answer: "B. Sanding",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. In multiple soldering joints should be covered with loam to prevent",
A: "fire scales.",
B: "glowing.",
C: "melting.",
D: "re-crystallization.",
answer: "A. Fire scales",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Broken pieces of glass can be made finer by",
A: "sanding.",
B: "planishing.",
C: "pulverizing.",
D: "crushing.",
answer: "C. Pulverizing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following towns in Ashanti region is most popular for glass bead production?",
A: "Bonwire",
B: "Dabaa",
C: "Ntonso",
D: "Koforidua",
answer: "D. Koforidua",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Silver omaments are further enhanced by",
A: "buffing.",
B: "gilding.",
C: "pickling.",
D: "lacquering.",
answer: "B. Gilding",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Nitric acid is suitable for etching",
A: "aluminium.",
B: "copper.",
C: "lead.",
D: "zinc.",
answer: "B. Copper",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. | The most appropriate emery paper for the initial sanding of jewellery item is",
A: "200 grits.",
B: "400 grits.",
C: "600 grits.",
D: "800 grits.",
answer: "A. 200 grits",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. In metal jewellery, carat represents",
A: "glossiness.",
B: "shape.",
C: "size.",
D: "weight.",
answer: "D. Weight",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. In indigenous Ghanaian culture, the colour brown is a symbol of",
A: "abundance and life.",
B: "decay and rottenness.",
C: "life and royalty.",
D: "wealth and power.",
answer: "B. Decay and rottenness",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following pairs of materials is petroleum based?",
A: "Acetate and jade",
B: "Perspex and sapphire",
C: "Polythene and perspex",
D: "Ruby and plypropylene",
answer: "C. Polythene and perspex",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. —_Injewellery production, killed spirit",
A: "acts as a catalyst.",
B: "aids in melting and flow of solder.",
C: "hardens the solder during the process.",
D: "reduces the temperature of the metal.",
answer: "B. Aids in melting and flow of solder",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]